Sigmund Freud Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Family Papers, 1851-1978 (Box 1-14)
  - Correspondence with Sigmund Freud, 1876-1974 (Box 1-12)
    - Bernays, Minna
      - 1882-1883
      - 1884
      - 1885
      - 1886
      - 1887
      - 1889-1898
      - 1910
      - 1913
      - 1922, 1930-1931, 1938, undated
    - Freud, Adolfine (“Dolfi”) (sister), 1885, 1915, 1924-1930, 1938
    - Freud, Alexander (brother)
      - 1901-1918
      - 1919-1924
      - 1926-1929
      - 1930-1938
    - Freud, Amalia (mother) (Box 2)
      - Originals, 1885-1886, 1917-1923, undated
      - Photocopies and transcripts, 1918-1929
    - Freud, Anna (daughter)
      - Letters
        - From Freud
          - 1904-1912
          - 1913-1914
          - 1915-1917
          - 1918-1919
          - 1920
          - 1921-1922
          - 1923-1926
          - 1927
          - 1928-1938
        - To Freud
          - 1910-1913
          - 1914-1916
          - 1917-1919
          - 1920
          - 1921
          - 1922
          - 1923-1928
          - 1929-1930
      - Miscellaneous related material, notes, and attachments, 1891-1923, undated
    - Freud, Emanuel (half brother), 1886, 1903-1914, undated, with an unidentified item regarding Emanuel and Philip Freud (half brother), undated
    - Freud, Ernestine Drucker (daughter-in-law), 1939, with cover letter from her to K. R. Eissler, 1952
    - Freud, Ernst L. (son) (Box 3)
      - 1918-1919
      - 1920-1921
      - 1922-1927
      - 1928-1931
      - 1932-1938
    - Freud, Gabriel (grandson), 1933-1938, 1974
    - Freud, Harry (nephew), 1926, 1938
    - Freud, Lucie (daughter-in-law), 1923-1933
    - Freud, Margarethe (Magnus) (niece), 1915-1931, with notes by her, 1964-1965
    - Freud, Marie (“Mitzi”) (sister)
      - 1888, 1901-1923, with letter from Anna Freud to K. R. Eissler, 1973
      - 1924-1939
    - Freud, Martha (wife)
      - “Brautbriefe”
        - Originals (Box 3, Reel 1)
          Available on microfilm. Shelf no. 15,960
          - 1882
            - June
            - July 1-13
            - July 14-31
            - Aug. 1-15
            - Aug. 16-30
            - Sept.
            - Oct.
            - Nov. (Box 4, Reel 1)
            - Dec.
          - 1883
            - Mar.-May
            - June 9-22
            - June 23-30
            - July 1-8
            - July 9-16
            - July 17-23
            - July 24-Aug. 1
            - Aug. 1-9 (Box 4, Reel 2)
            - Aug. 10-17
            - Aug. 18-22
            - Aug. 23-31
            - Sept. 1-6
            - Sept. 7-13
            - Sept. 15-22
            - Sept. 23-30
            - Oct. 1-17
            - Oct. 18-31
            - Nov. 1-12
            - Nov. 13-20
            - Nov. 21-30
            - Dec. 1-9 (Box 5, Reel 2)
            - Dec. 10-20
            - Dec. 21-31
          - 1884 (Box 5, Reel 3)
            - Jan. 1-14
            - Jan. 16-31
            - Feb. 1-12
            - Feb. 13-29
            - Mar. 1-15
            - Mar. 17-31
            - Apr. 1-14
            - Apr. 15-30
            - May 1-15
            - May 16-31
            - June 1-15
            - June 16-July 1
            - July 2-17
            - July 18-23
            - July 24-31
            - Aug. 2-15 (Box 5, Reel 4)
            - Aug. 17-31
            - Sept.
            - Oct. 1-16 (Box 6, Reel 4)
            - Oct. 17-Nov. 1
            - Nov. 2-14
            - Nov. 14-30
            - Dec. 1-18
            - Dec. 20-31
          - 1885
            - Jan. 1-15
            - Jan. 16-31
            - Feb. 2-15
            - Feb. 16-28
            - Mar. 1-13
            - Mar. 15-31
            - Apr. 1-14
            - Apr. 16-30
            - May 1-15
            - May 17-31
            - June 1-14 (Box 6, Reel 5)
            - June 15-30
            - July 1-15 (Box 7, Reel 5)
            - July 16-31
            - Aug. 1-15
            - Aug. 17-29
            - Oct. 11-18
            - Oct. 19-Nov. 1
            - Nov. 2-13
            - Nov. 14-29
            - Dec. 1-9
            - Dec. 11-31
          - 1886
            - Jan. 2-16
            - Jan. 17-31
            - Feb. 1-12
            - Feb. 13-26
            - Mar. 3-15
            - Mar. 16-31
            - Apr. 1-12
            - Apr. 14-29
            - May 1-13
            - May 15-31
            - June 1-17 (Box 8, Reel 5)
            - June 18-30
            - July
            - Aug.-Sept.
        - Transcripts (Box 8)
          - 1882
            - June
            - July 1-13
            - July 14-31
            - Aug. 1-13
            - Aug. 14-30
            - Sept.-Oct.
            - Nov.-Dec.
          - 1883
            - Mar.-June
            - July
            - Aug.
            - Sept. (Box 9)
            - Oct.
            - Nov.
    - Other letters
      - From Freud
        - 1887-1891
        - 1892
        - 1893
        - 1894
        - 1895
        - 1896
        - 1897
        - 1898
        - 1899, 1902
        - Undated
      - To Freud
        - 1887-1893
        - 1910-1913 (Box 10)
        - 1922
        - 1930
        - Undated or incomplete dates
      - “Reisebriefe” For additional material see Container 9, Other letters, From Freud
        - 1900
        - 1901
        - 1902
        - 1903-1904
        - 1905
        - 1907
        - 1908
        - 1909
        - 1910
        - 1911
        - 1912, 1915
        - 1918-1928
        - 1929-1932
    - Freud, Martin (son)
      - Originals and photocopies
        - 1910-1914
        - 1916-1919
        - 1920-1929
        - 1930-1938
      - Transcripts
        - 1910-1918
        - 1919-1937 (Box 11)
    - Freud, Moritz (cousin and brother-in-law), 1911, 1918, with letter from Diana J. Rendell to K. R. Eissler, 1973
    - Freud, Oliver and Henny Fuchs (son and daughter-in-law), 1905, 1910-1917, 1924-1925, 1933
    - Freud, Samuel (nephew)
      - Photocopies
        - 1911-1920
        - 1921-1925
        - 1926-1929
        - 1930-1938, undated
      - Transcripts
        - 1911-1923
        - 1924-1938
    - Freud, Theo (nephew), 1922
    - Freud, W. Ernest (grandson), 1924-1936
    - Freud-Marlé, Lilly (niece), and Arnold Marlé, 1911-1939, undated
    - Graf, Heinrich (brother-in-law), 1896, 1903, 1931
    - Graf, Rosa Freud (sister)
      - Originals
        - 1876, 1882-1885
        - 1886-1894, 1905-1911, undated
      - Photocopies, 1889, 1929, 1940, undated
      - Transcripts, 1876-1909, undated
    - Halberstadt, “Grandmother,” 1920, 1926
    - Halberstadt, Max and Sophie Freud (son-in-law and daughter)
      - 1908-1913
      - 1914-1915
      - 1916-1918 (Box 12)
      - 1919-1922
      - 1923-1932, undated
    - Hartwig, Pauline Freud (niece), 1931, 1937-1938
    - Heller, Judith Bernays (niece) and Victor, 1909-1911, 1916-1922
    - Hollitscher, Mathilde Freud and Robert (daughter and son-in-law)
      - 1898, 1907-1908
      - 1909-1912
      - 1917-1936
    - Loewenstein, Sophie Freud (granddaughter), 1938-1939
    - Magnus, Erwin, 1927, with a note on his relationship with Freud, 1957
    - Weiner, Lucy (niece), 1925
    - Winternitz, Paula, 1885
    - Winternitz, Pauline Freud (sister), 1937-1938
    - Collectively addressed letters by Freud
      - 1900, May 20, to Margarethe, Lilly, and Martha Freud (nieces)
      - 1909, Sept. 16, to family from Putnam's Camp, Keene Valley, N.Y., with additional background material, 1962
      - 1911, July 12, to family
      - 1926, 1929, 1935, 1938, miscellaneous notes to children
  - Correspondence between Others, 1870-1976 (Box 12-13)
    Correspondence between members of the Freud and Bernays families other than Sigmund Freud and between family members and persons outside the family. Some of the correspondence is accompanied by explanatory letters and notes.
    Arranged alphabetically by name of letter writer, then alphabetically by name of recipient, and thereunder chronologically. Correspondence with persons outside the family is filed under the name of the family member with whom they corresponded.
    - Bernays, Berman, to (Box 12)
      - Bernays, Emmeline, 1870
      - Bernays, Louis, 1879
    - Bernays, Edward L., to
      - Freud, Anna, 1958
      - Jones, Ernest, 1953-1956
    - Bernays, Eli, to
      - Freud, Martha, 1886
      - Unidentified person concerning Fritz Wahle, undated
    - Bernays, Emmeline
      - From
        - Fleischhacker, Hanchen, 1878-1879
        - Wahle, Richard, 1886
      - To
        - Bernays, Berman, 1851, undated
        - Unidentified person, birthday poem, 1875
    - Bernays, Louis, to
      - Bernays, Eli, 1882
      - Bernays, Emmeline, 1880-1881
    - Bernays, [Michael?], to Emmeline Bernays, 1879-1881
    - Bernays, Minna, to
      - Bernays, Eli, 1883
      - Freud, Martha, 1898, 1912
    - Freud, Adolfine, to
      - Bernays, Anna Freud, 1896
      - Freud, Martha, 1885
    - Freud, Alexander, to
      - Freud sisters, 1938-1940
      - Hollitscher, Mathilde Freud, 1928
    - Freud, Amalia, to
      - Bernays, Anna Freud, concerning the death of Jacob Freud, 1896
      - Freud, Marie, with note by Adolfine Freud, undated
    - Freud, Anna
      - From
        - Calceto, [?], 1914
        - Pichler, Hans, 1938
        - Rank, Otto, 1920
      - To Samuel Freud, 1920
    - Freud, Emanuel, to Eli Bernays, 1892
    - Freud, Ernst L.
      - From
        - Eissler, K. R., 1969, with attachments, 1932-1969
        - Grinstein, Alexander, 1969
        - Knoepfmacher, Hugo, 1961
        - Miscellaneous individuals, 1938, 1964, 1969, undated
      - To Oliver Freud, 1958, 1968
      - With Ludwig Binswanger, 1959
    - Freud, Jacob (father), to
      - Freud, Martha, 1884, 1892
      - Granddaughters, 1892
      - Hollitscher, Mathilde Freud, 1894
    - Freud, Lucie
      - From Princess Marie Bonaparte, 1950
      - To Felix Augenfeld, 1939, 1973, 1976
    - Freud, Margarethe (Magnus), to Marie Freud, 1942
    - Freud, Marie, to Hermann Waldinger, 1941
    - Freud, Martha
      - From
        - Bernays, Emmeline, 1904
        - Bonaparte, Marie, Princess, and George, Prince of Greece and Denmark, 1938-1949, undated (Box 13)
        - Breuer, Mathilde, 1887
        - Brunswick, Ruth Mack, 1940
        - Fliess, Ida, 1896-1897
        - Hammerschlag, Betty and Samuel, 1896
        - Jung, C. G. and Emma, 1907
        - Miscellaneous, 1938-1939
        - Rie, Oscar, 1904
        - Schönberg, Ignaz, 1881-1885
        - Zweig, Arnold, 1941, 1946
      - To
        - Augenfeld, Felix, 1946
        - Bernays, Emmeline and Minna, with postscripts by Sigmund Freud
          - 1886
            - Sept.-Oct.
            - Nov.-Dec.
          - 1887
            - Jan.-Mar.
            - Apr.-June
            - July-Dec.
          - 1893
        - Bernays, Hella Freud, 1939
        - Eitingon, M., 1917
        - Freud, Adolfine, 1938
        - Freud, Amalia, 1929
        - Freud, Ernestine Drucker, 1943
        - Freud, Marie, 1904
        - Freud sisters, 1939
        - Freud-Marlé, Lilly, 1936-1938, undated
        - Götzl, F., 1939
        - Hitschmann, Eduard and wife, 1950
        - Hollitscher, Mathilde Freud, 1949, 1951
        - Jerusalem, Anna, 1939, 1947
        - Krafft, Margaret R., 1939
        - Kris, Marianne, 1941, 1947-1950, with note from Paula Fichtl to Kris, 1948
        - Kvergic, Gertrude, 1938
        - Loewenstein, Paul, 1949
        - Loewenstein, Sophie Freud, 1945
        - Pfister, Oskar, 1939
        - Reiss, Elsa, 1939-1951
        - Steiner, Maximilian, 1941
        - Zweig, Frederika, 1948
        - Unidentified, undated
    - Freud, Martin
      - From Felix Deutsch, 1958
      - To
        - Brun, Rudolf, 1936
        - Freud, Martha, 1910, 1939
        - Reiss, Elsa, 1946
    - Freud, Philipp, to Marie Freud, 1902
    - Freud, Samuel
      - To
        - Freud, Harry, 1944
        - Winternitz, Pauline Freud, 1919
      - With James Strachey, 1920-1922
    - Freud, W. Ernest, to
      - Eissler, K. R., 1970
      - Halberstadt, Eva, possibly in the hand of Sophie Freud Halberstadt, 1919
    - Graf, Rosa Freud, to Minna Bernays, undated
    - Halberstadt, Sophie Freud, to Marie Beutel Nagel, undated
    - Winternitz, Valentin, to Amalia and Jacob Freud, 1896
  - Subject File, 1851-1978 (Box 13-14)
    Legal documents, estate records, correspondence, writings, school records, immigration papers, certificates, genealogical data, photograph, and printed matter pertaining to or collected by members of the Freud and Bernays families.
    Arranged alphabetically by name of family member and therein by topic or type of material.
    - Bernays, Bermann, probate and employment records, 1878-1882 (Box 13)
    - Bernays, Edward L., draft of “My Uncle Sigi,” undated
    - Bernays, Emmeline
      - Legal documents, 1879-1880
      - Poem written by her on Bermann Bernays's wedding anniversary, 1862
    - Bernays, Jacob, last will and testament, 1873-1881
    - Bernays, Minna, bequest of Cornelia Dub, 1939
    - Bernays family, miscellaneous correspondence, poetry, and sketch, 1877-1889, undated
    - Freud, Amalia and Jacob
      - Death certificate of Amalia Freud, 1930
      - Domicile certificate, 1927
      - Good conduct certificate, 1859
      - Marriage certificate, 1855, 1859
      - Miscellaneous legal documents, including Freud family birth and death data, 1851-1955, 1988 See also Oversize
      - Testament drafted by Amalia Freud, 1918 (Box 14)
    - Freud, Ernst L., evaluation of correspondence between Freud and C. G. Jung, 1970
    - Freud, Josef, documents regarding conviction for counterfeiting rubles, 1865-1866 See Oversize
    - Freud, Lucian (grandson), exhibit catalog and clipping, 1959, 1978
    - Freud, Martha
      - Death of, condolence letters to Anna Freud, 1951
        - Folder 1
        - Folder 2
        - Folder 3
        - Folder 4
      - Ruben family tree, undated
      - Scenic postcard, Villa Satori, Traunsee, Austria, and dried flowers on card from Gloggnitz, Austria, undated
    - Freud, Martin
      - New Year's greetings, 1897-1900, undated
      - Poem to mother, 1932
      - Reminiscence by August Beranek of meeting with Martin Freud, undated
      - School report, 1898-1899
    - Freud, Moritz, memorial book with calendar of kaddish dates, 1920
    - Freud, Oliver
      - New Year's greetings, 1897-1900, undated
      - School report, 1898-1899
    - Heller, Judith Bernays, “Freud's Mother and Father,” 1956
    - Waldinger, Ernst, poems about Freud, 1969
    - Winternitz, Pauline Freud
      - Immigration papers, 1892-1941
      - Marriage certificate, 1895
    - Winternitz, Valentin, death certificate, 1900
    - Unidentified and miscellaneous items, 1878, 1908, undated
- General Correspondence, 1871-1996 (Box 14-44)
  Correspondence including original letters, photocopies, transcripts, translations, and related background material between Sigmund Freud and professional associates, friends, students, patients, and the public.
  Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent and therein chronologically. Unidentified correspondence is filed at the end of the series.
  - Abraham, Hedwig, 1926, 1933-1936 (Box 14)
  - Abraham, Karl
    Available on microfilm. Shelf no. 19,545
    - From Freud
      - 1907-1910
      - 1911-1913
      - 1914
      - 1915-1919 (Box 15)
      - 1920-1926
    - To Freud
      - 1907-1909
      - 1910-1913
      - 1914-1915
      - 1916-1919
      - 1920-1923
      - 1924-1925
  - Abrahamsen, David, 1938-1939
  - Achelis, Werner, 1927-1928, with background data provided by him, undated
  - Acton, William, 1939
  - Adam, Robert, 1909
  - Adler, Alfred
    - From Freud, 1899-1911, undated
    - To Freud, 1910-1911
  - Adler, Paul, 1920
  - Aichhorn, August, 1930
  - Albert, Georg, 1927
  - Aldington, Hilda, 1939
  - Alexander, Franz, with cover letter from him to Ernest Jones, 1954
    - 1921-1931
    - 1932-1936
  - American Guild for German Cultural Freedom, New York, N.Y., 1938
  - Andreas-Salomé, Lou (Box 16)
    - From Freud
      - Originals
        - 1912-1915
        - 1916-1918
        - 1919-1924
        - 1925-1936
      - Transcripts
        - 1912-1918
        - 1919-1936
    - To Freud
      - Originals
        - 1912-1914
        - 1915-1916
        - 1917-1919
        - 1920-1923
        - 1924-1925
        - 1926-1930
        - 1931-1936
      - Transcripts
        - 1912-1916
        - 1917-1920
        - 1921-1925
        - 1926-1935
  - Baginsky, Adolf, 1886 (Box 17)
  - Barach, Alvan L., 1938
  - Barek, Dr. [?], 1936, 1938
  - Bauer, Victor, 1931
  - Baum, Mrs. H., 1931
  - Baumberger, Yvonne, 1932
  - Baumgardt, David, 1932, 1938-1939, with biographical information on him, 1967
  - Beer-Hofmann, Richard, 1936
  - Benedek, Therese, 1926-1935
  - Bennet, E. A., 1930-1932
  - Benthal, V., 1936
  - Berdach, Rahel, 1938-1939
  - Berg, Charles, 1939
  - Bergmann, Samuel Hugo, 1926, 1936
  - Bermann, Ernst, 1938
  - Bermann, Richard A., 1938
  - Bermann-Fischer Verlag, 1938
  - Bernfeld, Siegfried, 1921-1925, 1931-1936
  - Bernheim, Hippolyte, 1891, undated
  - Betz, Wilhelm, 1907-1911, with letter from Charles Hamilton to K. R. Eissler, 1957
  - Bianchini, Marco Levy, 1925
  - Bibring, Edward, 1935-1938, undated
  - Bickel, Lothar Eliezer, 1931
  - Bieber, Ann, 1920-1925
  - Binswanger, Ludwig
    - Originals, 1912-1936
    - Photocopies and transcripts
      - 1908-1910
      - 1911
      - 1912
      - 1913
      - 1914-1919
      - 1920-1926
      - 1927-1938
  - Bivin, Dr. [?], 1925
  - Bjerre, Poul, 1924 (Box 18)
  - Blanton, Smiley, 1929
  - Bleuler, Eugen
    - 1905-1910, circa 1960
    - 1911-1912
    - 1913-1914, 1925-1937
  - Blüher, Hans
    - Carbon copies of letters to Freud, 1912-1913
    - Originals and transcripts of letters from Freud, 1912-1913
    - Published edition edited by John Neubauer, 1996
  - Blumenthal, Mr. [?], 1924
  - Blumgart, Leonard, 1921-1931
  - Bluth, [?], 1936
  - B'nai B'rith, 1926, 1931, 1937
  - Boehm, Felix, 1919-1929
  - Bonaparte, Marie, Princess, 1927, 1936-1938
  - Boren, William, 1920
  - Bornstain, M., 1920
  - Bose, Girindrashekhar
    - Originals
      - From Freud, 1921-1937
      - To Freud, 1921-1933
    - Transcripts and published edition, 1921-1937, 1964
  - Brasch, Elise, 1936
  - Braun, Ludwig, 1936-1938
  - Braun-Vogelstein, Julie, 1927
  - Breuer, Josef, Mathilde, and Robert
    - From Freud, 1884-1907, 1926, 1937
    - To Freud, 1884-1925
  - Breyer, Ferdinand, 1927
  - Brill, A. A.
    - From Freud
      - Originals
        - 1908-1910
        - 1911-1912
        - 1913-1915
        - 1919-1923
        - 1924-1929
        - 1930-1933 (Box 19)
        - 1934-1939
      - Transcripts and translations
        - 1908-1911
        - 1912-1919
        - 1920-1939
    - To Freud
      - Originals
        - 1908-1914
        - 1936-1939
      - Transcripts, 1908-1939
  - British Broadcasting Corp., 1938-1939
  - Brod, Max, 1913
  - Brücke, Franz Theodor von, 1932
  - Brun, Rudolph, 1936, undated
  - Brunswick, Cecile, 1930-1932
  - Brunswick, Mark, 1924, 1929, 1934-1937
  - Brunswick, Ruth Mack
    - 1921-1925
    - 1926
    - 1927
    - 1928
    - 1929 (Box 20)
      - Jan.-Apr.
      - May-Oct.
    - 1930-1932
    - 1933-1937
    - 1938-1939
  - Bryan, Douglas, 1925
  - Bryher, Winifred, circa 1938
  - Buber, Martin, 1908, with cover letter from him to K. R. Eissler, 1960
  - Bullitt, William C., 1938
  - Burlingham, Dorothy T. and Robert, with postscripts by M. Eitingon and Martha Freud, 1931-1938
  - Burrow, Trigant
    - From Freud, 1913-1927, 1935
    - To Freud, 1924-1927, 1935
  - Calveira, Amilcar, 1935
  - Carossa, Hans, 1939
  - Carrington, Hereward, 1921, with letter from him to Ernest Jones, 1954
  - Carstens, Erik, 1933
  - Cassirer Bernfeld, Suzanne, 1933-1938 For additional material see Container 42, United States consul
  - Castro, Abel de, 1924-1929
  - Centralblatt, 1912
  - Challaye, Félicien, 1939
  - Charcot, J. M.
    - 1885-1890
    - 1891-1892, undated
  - Charles, Jean I., 1928
  - Christoffel, Hans, 1939
  - Chrobak, Rudolf, undated
  - Claparède, Edouard, 1905-1911
  - Clark, Dr. [?], 1927
  - Clark, Pierce, 1927
  - Clemens, Cyril, 1930
  - Cohen, Israel, 1938, with letter and clipping from the Central Zionist Archives, Jerusalem, Israel, 1954, 1980
  - Coles, S. Ann, 1938, with recollections by her, undated
  - Committee of Austrians in England, London, England, circa 1938
  - Coriat, Isador H., 1921, 1925
  - Coudenhove-Kalergi, Richard N., 1925, 1931
  - Crouzet, Guy, 1938
  - Czuczka, Ernst, 1938
  - Danninger, Kornel, 1933 (Box 21)
  - Darmstädter, Ludwig, 1910, 1918, 1926
  - Datta, D. L., 1938-1939
  - Davis, Hilda, 1938
  - Davison, Corene C., 1929
  - Delgado, Honorio, 1919-1934
  - Deri, Frances, 1935
  - Deuticke, Franz, [1908], 1910, 1918, 1925, 1937-1938
  - Deutsch, Felix
    - 1923
    - 1924-1926
  - Deutsch, Helene, 1913, 1924-1931, 1938, undated
  - Deutsch, Leo, 1938
  - Dirsztay, Viktor von, Baron, 1920, with a note by K. R. Eissler, 1959
  - Doolittle, Hilda, undated
  - Dormandi, Ladislas, 1931
  - Doryon, Y'isra'el
    - From Freud, 1938
    - To Freud, 1938-1939
  - Downey, Helen, 1922
  - Druyanow, Alter, 1910
  - Dubowitz, Margit, 1920-1921
  - Dumas, Georges, 1922
  - Dyer-Bennett, Richard, 1928, 1933
  - Eastman, Max, 1926-1936
    Available on microfilm. Shelf no. 9781.2
  - Eckstein, Emma
    - 1895-1903
    - 1904-1910, undated
  - Edinburgh Medical University, Edinburgh, Scotland, 1939
  - Editors of various psychoanalytic journals, 1933
  - Eeden, Frederik van, 1914
  - Ehrenstein, Albert, 1912
  - Eichhorn, Lothar, 1930
  - Einstein, Albert, concerning Why War?
    - Letters from Einstein, 1929-1939
    - Letters from Freud
      - 1929-1931
      - 1932-1936
    - Published edition by the Chicago Institute of Psychoanalysis, Chicago, Ill., 1978
    - Related correspondence
      - 1931-1932
      - 1937-1969
  - Einstein, Carl, 1930
  - Eitingon, M. (Box 22)
    - From Freud
      - 1906-1907
      - 1909-1912
      - 1913-1914
      - 1915-1916
      - 1917-1918
      - 1919
      - 1920
        - Jan.-Apr.
        - May-Dec.
      - 1921
      - 1922
        - Jan.-June
        - July-Dec.
      - 1923
      - 1924
      - 1925
      - 1926 (Box 23)
        - Jan.-July
        - Sept.-Dec.
      - 1927
        - Jan.-May
        - June-Aug.
        - Sept.-Dec.
      - 1928
        - Jan.-Apr.
        - June-Dec.
      - 1929
        - Jan.-May
        - June-Dec.
      - 1930
        - Jan.-Apr.
        - May-Aug.
        - Sept.-Dec.
      - 1931
        - Jan.-Apr.
        - May-Aug.
        - Oct.-Dec.
      - 1932
        - Jan.-Mar.
        - Apr.-July
        - Aug.-Dec.
      - 1933 (Box 24)
      - 1934-1935
      - 1937-1939
      - Envelopes, with note by Anna Freud, undated
    - To Freud
      - Originals, 1913, 1922, 1931, 1933
      - Photocopies
        - 1906-1915
        - 1916-1919
        - 1920-1921
        - 1922-1924
        - 1925-1926
        - 1927
        - 1928
        - 1929
        - 1930
        - 1931
        - 1932
        - 1933-1939
  - Eliasberg, Wladimir, 1926-1928, undated
  - Ellis, Havelock, 1912, 1923-1928, 1934, 1938 (Box 25)
  - Engel, Paul, 1928
  - Eugenie, Princess, granddaughter of George I, King of the Hellenes, 1939
  - Fackel-Kraus, 1906 See also Container 29, Hirschfeld, Magnus
  - Fairbairn, W. Ronald D., 1920-1921
  - Federation of the German Youth Movement, 1933
  - Federn, Paul
    - Originals, 1908-1915, 1925-1929, 1934 For additional material see Container 138, Federn, Paul
    - Photocopies and transcripts
      - 1905-1910
      - 1911-1917
      - 1918-1924
      - 1925-1928
      - 1929-1931
      - 1932-1938, undated
  - Fehl, Siegfried, 1935
  - Feigenbaum, Dorian, 1920
  - Ferenczi, Sándor